Matías Micheletto

Ph.D. | Electronic Engineer | Front-End Developer

Personal information

Full name: Micheletto, Matías Cel.: -

Email: - Portfolios: beacons - github - linkedin - google

About

I have worked almost 10 years in the field of technology, the last five of which have been spent mostly on front-end web development, oriented both to desktop and mobile applications and using offline-first and distributed paradigms. I have worked in professional and also academic environments, independently or as part of larger multidisciplinary teams. I have published several articles in international journals, won innovation competitions and participated in dozens of national and international conferences.

Experience

2016 - present | CONICET | Research scholar

Research topics: *Embedded and LPWAN based real-time systems, scientific computing.* Approved application for the position of assistant researcher at CONICET.

2016 - present | INTA (E.E.A. H. Ascasubi) | IT Consultant and front-end developer

Development and maintenance of several mobile apps: Campero (2020), Campero Fertilizadoras (2021, awarded CITA 2022), Criollo (2022), Criollo Atomizadores (2022), Criollo Mochilas (2022) and El Galpón (2023). Stack: ReactJS 18, Framework7, CapacitorJS, AngularJS, Apache Cordova.

2019 - 2020 | CAPP Mobile BB S.R.L. (spinned off to NuQlea) | Front-end developer

Development and maintenance of the mobile app, backoffice and administrator panel. Stack: AngularJS, Bootstrap, Framework7, Apache Cordova, Firebase.

2017 - 2019 | Neufitech S.R.L. | IT Consultant and front-end developer

Development and maintentance of the online neuro-psichological activities platform (PsiMESH). Design and implementation of IoT devices for communication and mobility assistance for people with disabilities (EyeRobot). Stack: AngularJS, Materialize, Firebase, Tobii Eyetracker, ESP8266.

2016 - 2020 | National University of the South | Teaching assistant & chief of lab activities

Undergraduate courses: Digital Circuits and Logic Design.

2014 - 2015 | National University of the South (DIEC) | Intern front-end developer

Development of an online multimedia physics book. Stack: jQuery, ThreeJS.

Education

2020 | Ph.D. Engineering – National University of the South (Bahía Blanca, Buenos Aires)

Completed eight posgraduate courses (eq. 628 hs). GPA: 100%.

2016 | Electronic Engineer – National University of the South (Bahía Blanca, Buenos Aires)

Participated in a student essay contest. Completed a full-year college internship. GPA: 81.7%.

Skills (exp. in years)

Front-End development tools: React (4), AngularJS (2), WebAssembly (1), css (MUI, Bootstrap, Framework7).

Programming languages: JavaScript (10), C/C++ (10), Python (3), Matlab (10).

Hybrid and mobile technologies: CapacitorJS (3), Apache Cordova (4), Android Studio (4).

Other Tools: Git (10), NodeJS (5), Linux (10), Emscripten (1).

Other: Scientific computing - 3D Design and modeling - Circuits design - Digital content creation - Teaching & coaching.

Achievements

- Three-time winner in tech innovation marathons (Agrotón 2018, Agrotón 2021, AuravantHack 2022).
- Published ten articles in international journals, participated in 20+ national and international conferences.
- Published two courses as Udemy Instructor with more than 3000 active students.
- Six-time awarded research scholarships for undergraduate, posgraduate and posdoctorate students.
- Development of two MVPs as independent developer: Agrar.io and Presipedia.

Language

English: B2-Upper Intermediate (Listening: B1-Intermediate. Reading: C2-Proficient).

Spanish: Native speaker.